Everyone's online trying to teach you how
to get rich.
In this video,
I'm actually going to teach you how to get
free.
Because rewind 10 years, my job
is working in a gym.
I'm counting people's reps,
I'm doing their workouts.
Today,
I have over four seven-figure businesses.
But irrespective of the money,
I get to work from wherever I want in the
world.
Last week, I was in Dubai. This week,
I'm back in Sydney.
And as long as I've got my laptop
and an internet connection,
I can provide for my
family, buy nice things, drive nice cars.
And the truth of the matter is this,
your first $1,000 is going to be the
hardest.
You'll need the same amount of effort to
go from naught to 1,000 that you will to
go from 1 to 10,000.
And it's probably about the same amount of
effort to go from
10,000 to 100,000. And today,
we're going to do this video in reverse
order.
So first of all,
to pick your perfect customer.
In marketing, we call this an avatar.
And in essence,
you might have noticed that
when you watch adverts on TV, even the
voice of the person in the advert
is the avatar they're talking to.
A Range Rover advert will,
"Head down to your local Range Rover
dealership
today." Whereas maybe for a pickup truck
it's, "Check out the new Toyota Hilux.
With over a five-year warranty." They even
talk in the voice of the person that's
buying. Now, for many of you,
I would say model your avatar off your
best client.
In every video,
you're talking to your best client.
Even right now, the language, the pacing,
the cadence, everything I say, I know my
perfect client in mind.
You've probably got some level of
in-person mastery,
physio, PT, accountant, whatever.
But you're looking to take
that online because the majority of you
sell an hour of
your time for a set amount of money.
But when you go online,
you can change that.
When you have online personal training
clients, things change.
Let's say you're charging £45 per hour.
You might remodel that
and charge someone online £45 per week.
In person, they get their workout program,
they get to be in the gym with you, they
get to ask you questions.
But you can flip that,
and here you can say, "I'm going
to give you program and support." Which
is what they're paying you for in person.
But the beauty is,
once you write their program,
you give it to them, and you give
them the support. Sometimes
that £45 per week client can be
serviced in 30 minutes, some weeks 15.
And that's how you get to accelerate your
hourly rate, by servicing people in
shorter periods of time.
Once you create assets, communities,
maybe even onboard an
assistant coach,
suddenly you're not restricted to only
earning £45 per hour.
So let's go back a step.
The sale's going to have to occur at some
point.
Now, at this point,
they've probably watched quite a lot of
your content, they've
read a lot of your emails,
and they're bought into you.
Now, one thing I will say is this,
a lot of you out there want to charge
people for
three or six months up front because it
benefits you.
The reality is that the longer a client
stays with you, the less work you're going
to need to do.
But because this first month
is very labor-intensive, we seem to
think, well, we might as well get three
or four months out of them up front.
And business gurus will tell you to do
that because if you get four months of
someone's revenue and bring it forward,
and you close five, 10 clients, it means
you have a massive month.
And then the business guru
that you've hired can go,
"When I started working with James, he
was only making two grand a month."
"What'd
you make last month,
James?" "14K last month." But really,
they're taking months
of revenue and backdating it.
Despite what people say on the internet,
I think you
should charge people weekly or monthly.
You should give them rolling costs.
The same way that if Netflix tomorrow said
you have to pay annually, even if you
love Netflix, it might put you off.
You're going to go,
"I like paying for it monthly." It's a
cash flow thing.
So many of the services
that we use online,
although they're cheaper to do
annually, we still do them monthly.
It's cash flow, it's convenience.
It's not feeling tied into something,
just in case it gets crap.
Everything that you want for the sale,
put your client in mind.
Another thing you can do is a guarantee.
That's another way of taking the risk from
your client and taking it on yourself.
Last weekend in Dubai,
I did a business mentorship event
and hosted over 100
people to help them talk through all of
these things.
Now,
I charged people quite a bit of money to
come along to the event, so I gave
them a guarantee. I said, "Okay,
if by lunchtime,
this event isn't everything that
you think it is and more, let me know.
I'll refund your ticket,
I'll refund your flight,
and I'll refund your hotel." That
can sometimes just be the little thing
someone needs to put them over the edge to
come along to the event
and get there in person.
I took the risk from their shoulders
and put it on mine.
And one final thing to think is
that you charge based on demand.
That's where your price is set.
Not how many qualifications you've got,
not even
how much experience you've got.
How many people are queuing up to do
business with
you? For instance,
I'm due a price rise very soon for my
business mentorship
because I just had to take it offline for
a month because I was too busy.
I want you to think about it this way.
As a golden rule, if you are full,
you're too cheap,
and you should have a certain
amount of hours or clients that
is your capacity in-person or online.
And if you're not full,
you're not marketing hard enough.
So you're always going to be in
that balance between full, raise prices,
not full,
do more marketing. Even now,
I'm still marketing the shit out of my
mentorship,
even though it's currently closed, so
that I have the leverage to increase
prices.
So for that sale to occur,
people need to land somewhere where they
can find out
everything about it. And for that,
we need something called a landing page.
So a landing page and a website
are two different things.
A website, you get onto it, it's about us,
contact us, testimonials.
There's loads of different places to
click.
A landing page has one outcome
and one outcome only. That is to buy.
Start off with a headline. Make a promise.
How to give up smoking without cravings.
How to lose weight without counting
calories.
How to pay less tax without getting
inquired by HMRC. Make a promise.
Make a statement. Sometimes
if your headline is quite short,
you can have a
subheading.
How to give up smoking without cravings.
Subheading, I'm making these up.
Over the next 12 weeks,
you're going to learn the
insert name method,
which has a 92% success rate
or your money back. Great.
Then we have something called a VSL,
which is a video sales letter.
If you go to any of my links in the
description,
every page where I have my offer,
there'll be a heading, subheading,
then a video of me just telling you what
it is.
"Hey,
this is my business mentorship where I
help small businesses make more money
online." "Hey,
welcome to Short-Form Content Mastery,
where I help people create
short-form content." The VSL gets to be
the best place to objection handle.
I'm not a big fan of sales calls.
I've never done a sales call in my life.
I tell people not to do sales calls
because if your landing page can tell you
everything that it needs to know
and gives you a guarantee,
I just don't know why
you need to sell to someone on the phone.
Yeah, sure,
if you're a high-end accountant
or you're a lawyer or there's some kind
of onboarding process,
but for the majority of you,
you should send traffic to this
landing page,
and they should be able to qualify
themselves in and qualify them
out. The VSL, no more than three minutes,
should be unscripted.
Just tell me what it is.
If you can't tell me three minutes about
what you do, then
give up, go back to recruitment.
And I say no fancy editing.
You've already won them over at this
point. And again,
don't introduce yourself.
"Hi, my name's James Smith
and I work with small..." Mate,
they know who you are by
the time they've got there,
and it'll make more sense when we go out.
Okay, there are some things
that we need to get in here.
In this order.
What it is, what they get,
why they need it, why to trust. That's it.
What it is.
It's a business mentorship course help to
help small businesses make money online.
What they get.
You get access to me in a Discord where I
critique your content,
look at your landing pages,
and I give you a video course library from
using
chatbots, editing, et cetera, et cetera.
Why you need it.
Because you're currently trying to build a
personal brand.
You're trying to move your business to be
more online, and you're currently putting
the effort in.
You're not getting the outcome
that you want because you're not
doing it right. Why to trust me.
Here's testimonials.
Here's a money-back guarantee. How to pay.
Click the button.
You should have some fun with your VSL.
So for instance, in the training world,
we might A/B split test GVT 10 by
10, or in the other block of training,
you might do five by two, whatever it is.
And then we look at our results in our
training, and we can determine whether or
not this works or this doesn't.
So with this,
if you use a platform like Leadpages,
you can duplicate the same page a few
times.
You can A/B split test the headline,
the subheading, the VSL.
You might even keep all of this bit the
same,
and you might just change this bit up
here.
We've seen this on YouTube at the moment.
Everyone's split testing their thumbnails
and their titles because one will perform
better than others. And
if one's at 2% conversion, 2% conversion,
4% conversion,
the 4% conversion one,
double the amount of business from the
same amount of
effort. So this is a very important thing.
Think of it like a menu for your business.
When you're perusing a restaurant on a
night out, you go up,
you have a look at the
menu, you have a little look inside,
you make a decision where you're going for
dinner. Wouldn't it be nice
if those restaurants said, "Hey,
if you don't love the
food, you get your money back"?
Next question.
How do you arrive at a landing page?
You can send people, but the reality
is the majority of people
are going to go to
that and never come back. So
if your funnel just sends people to a
landing page,
you're going to get a high bounce rate.
And if you could ever get someone on
social media to do what you want,
you should
get their email address. Now,
I'm going to break this up into two
places.
I think an autoresponder is a good idea.
It could be three emails, five emails,
30 emails. It could be whatever.
I was once in an autoresponder of 52
emails.
And basically,
this guy gave me 52 ways to benefit my
business, and every email was
amazing. On the last email,
he asked me to buy his book.
I didn't buy the book.
Then you can get a broadcast. And again,
in the links in the description, you're
going to see 30 Days and 30 Ways.
That's my autoresponder.
You should sign up to
that just so you can copy it.
The average person buys on day 19. Why?
I don't know And then you should also be
able to broadcast to this audience.
So very shortly, broadcasting is,
say something good happens to me today,
I'll
write an email.
Something bad happens to me today,
I'll write an email.
Black Friday, need to get my revenue up,
So that person who I read 52 of his
emails,
he would broadcast to me at the same
time. So I'd get the automation,
then I'd get a relevant email a few times
a week
about something he was up to.
On one of those emails,
he wrote it drunk from his
dad's funeral,
and at the end of his email, he did, "PS,
if you think it's
inappropriate to sell you my book off the
back of my dad's death, go fuck
yourself." And I bought the book off that.
So the autoresponder warmed me up,
nurtured me. The broadcast
is where I bought.
I use autoresponders in my business
mentorship.
I also bolt autoresponders onto the back
of lead magnets, which we get into a
second, then I broadcast on top.
Any of you that read my emails,
you'll now go,
"Oh, wow, yeah,
I remember the autoresponder." And, "Oh,
wait, I remember the
broadcast." Then again,
every email should contain a call to
action, which goes to
the landing page. Now, the reality
is some people will read your emails for
three
weeks, other people three months.
Sometimes they'll read them for a year.
The thing is,
if you can get them in a habit of always
reading your emails, there's
going to be a day where I call it the
right time effect.
They're going to sit down,
their button's going to pop off their
jeans, their
boyfriend's going to dump them,
or they're going to ask someone for their
number
and get rejected,
and it's the very next email
that comes in, which is where you
get them clicking through,
going to the landing page
and acquiring a new client.
The right time effect,
that's why you want to be emailing
or having something going
out daily, because if you don't
and someone else does,
they'll go with them.
I've done a whole course on email
marketing.
There's a link to
that in the description as well.
But fundamentally, this
is where you get to build a relationship
with someone.
If you can get someone reading your emails
every day while they're taking a poo,
man,
your sales are going to get a lot easier.
Golden rule, 20% of your audience,
your follower size,
should be on your email
list.
If you haven't got 20% of your audience on
your email list, your priorities
are in the wrong place. If it's sub 20%,
focus on growing the email list.
Even if your followers don't grow,
you should get that. Okay,
how do we get emails?
Very good point.
I call this a lead magnet.
I also call this a squeeze page.
Now, not a lot of the stuff that I do
is free,
but I have created a brand-new free
lead magnet course
that you get through in about 45 minutes.
There's a link to
that in the description as well.
Squeeze page two.
We basically need to create a page where
people give us their contact information.
Usually email address.
You can get phone number.
SMS is performing a little bit better
recently.
But we need to give something
that they want.
Not a free workout, not some free recipes,
something of value.
If someone was to walk down the street
and see you holding a sign,
would they come
up to you and inquire? If not,
really think about this.
Things that I've seen perform really
poorly are e-books,
because although people
might download your e-book,
they open it on their phone,
they read two pages, they
never come back to it.
Sometimes your lead magnet can actually be
the email
autoresponder. So for instance,
if you think back to what I just said
about that
guy who said,
"I'll give you 52 ways in 52 days," the
value wasn't in the course,
it was in the emails that I
was getting from him.
So sometimes you can literally have your
lead magnet, send them to the email list,
and give them the value in the email list.
You can sometimes give them an asset.
Stay there. For instance, this
was the lead magnet mastery thing
that I was holding
up in content. This performed amazing.
If you can print something out as a lead
magnet, my God, you can do well.
So then, can be an asset. Like I say,
if you print that out and hold it,
the amount
of emails you get is crazy.
Think we got 7,000 emails from just
that campaign.
So draft that up, only took me, like,
a few hours, got so many emails from it.
Now, another lead magnet
that I've used really well
is I do critiques on YouTube.
You might have seen them before,
where I go through people's pages.
In the link in the description,
you'll also see there's going to be a
critique
link. Now, interestingly enough,
if I tell people to go to the email
autoresponder
for 30 days,
we earn a good amount of money.
But if they come in to get their content
critiqued, I then chuck them in the 30-day
automation,
and we get twice the attributed revenue
from that. Why?
I don't know, but it works.
So the lead magnet's the things
that you're always
going to want to send people to,
and you're probably thinking,
"So how do we get
people onto the lead magnet?" We're
getting there.
So if we think of this as a lead magnet.
So for YouTube,
we very much like to give the link in the
description chat, and
then people can click on it because
there's a hyperlink.
Now, on Instagram and Facebook,
we can't hyperlink.
Well, you can on Facebook,
but let's just pretend these two.
You can put it in the comments,
but the best way we could do this
is utilize
ManyChat, which is a chatbot automation.
So you can give people cues where you say,
"Comment the word leads, and I will send
you this." So ManyChat can then be the
middle ground where you can say to people,
"Thank you very much for commenting
that word.
Here's a link to my lead magnet,"
and you can send them there.
Some people have been wondering,
ManyChat have just got a new feature this
week
about whether or not you should auto-DM
new followers.
Me personally,
I don't think you should do that.
Think of it like
when you go shopping for aftershave
or perfume, sometimes it's
better to give people space.
They can sniff a few, try it out.
"Excuse me,
can I buy this perfume?" What I don't like
the idea of is getting in
people's faces going, "Hello, sir.
Can I help you?
This fragrance is 20% off."
That just gets people to go, "Thank you.
No, thank you," and they leave.
So we want to be able to use call to
actions in
content. For short-form,
we're going to use
that to get to ManyChat.
In long-form, you'll notice
that even early on in this video,
I just tell you to go
down to the description
and pick it yourself.
So both of these ultimately do the same
thing, and then your lead magnet puts
people onto your email list. YouTube,
Instagram, lead magnet.
Lead magnet takes you on to emails.
Emails send people through to the landing
page.
Now, the next part, maybe the easiest,
maybe the hardest part, is that you then
need to get people to watch your content
online.
For YouTube, the most difficult thing
is going to be packaging content
that people
want to watch.
They don't want to watch how to lose
weight tracking calories.
They want to watch a video of how I lost
seven kilograms of fat in two months
without tracking my calories,
or whatever it is.
You might then even bundle
that into a challenge video, burning
and eating 10,000
calories in a day,
and you Trojan horse some kind of message
into that.
For short-form content,
we're going to have to stop people whilst
they are on a
doom scrolling mission.
We're going to have to get them with
hooks.
We're going to have to prioritize the
first three seconds.
Ultimately, there is a level of art
that needs to be done at every level on
the way
down. So whether short-form or long-form,
we need to be able to get people's
attention.
We need to solve enough problems
and generate enough of this magical
power called goodwill.
Once we get enough goodwill,
once we ask people to use a
call to action, they will listen.
If you haven't solved enough people's
problems
first,
they're just not going to be interested.
Once we've used the lead magnet,
we're going to send them to a squeeze
page.
We're going to get their information.
We're going to give them an asset.
We're going to critique them,
or we're going to send them into an
autoresponder.
We're going to give them loads
and loads of value where they go,
"Jesus Christ, I
can't believe I'm getting all this for
free." From the emails,
we'll probably have
some kind of autoresponder set up,
which means if it's a Friday
and they sign up
and you're not working over the weekend,
they still get nurtured over that weekend.
Then we're going to broadcast them on days
where we've got good news, bad news, a
story to tell, whatever it is.
Every email has a call to action there.
That call to action sends them onto a
landing page where we have our offer.
We have a headline, a subheading.
We have a VSL where we tell them exactly
what it
is. Three minutes, unscripted,
no fancy editing.
What it is, what they get,
why they need it, why they trust us,
how to pay.
We base all of our customers off the
perfect avatar.
Your avatar is your favorite client.
Those of you that
are charging per hour should be looking to
charging per week.
And you want to be able to create some
kind of online system where as you scale
the
business,
you can get to a point beyond the amount
of customers you could ever
have. As a face-to-face personal trainer,
I could only train 30 hours a week.
Ultimately, it was 15, 20 clients.
As of today, my coaching app,
I have 7,000 active clients.
We've got about eight coaches,
and we make millions.
For this business mentorship,
same process. For my coaching app,
same process.
My lead magnets for my coaching app
are calorie calculators,
just using the free
trial. My lead magnets for this
are all in the description.
I use emails on AWeber, Klaviyo,
Mailchimp, SendGrid, all for different
businesses that I run.
I have autoresponders set up,
whether you join me for
business, PT client, whatever.
Even for my business mentorship alone,
if you check
out all the links below,
you can actually look to exactly how I
create my landing
pages, and you can copy it.
You'll notice that I even use dark mode
for my landing
pages because I noticed there's a trend
that the majority of people on YouTube
seem
to prefer dark mode.
And I kind of have a good understanding of
who my customers
are.
I spent the weekend with a load of them in
Dubai.
And I know that a video like this would
make them feel like, "Oh,
do you know what?
Maybe they're not quite ready to buy my
stuff,
but they'll at least click the links
in the description,
check out my lead magnets." Half of you
might just want to copy
me and rip me off,
but then the other half of you might go,
"Wow, I'm going to hire
the person- Me.
Because I like the way
that James tried to acquire me as a
client,
and I want to use
that to acquire clients myself." So
hopefully that was very
helpful.
Hopefully you can find your way to the
links down there.
And if that's not enough
and you're thirsty for more information,
YouTube
recommends that you watch this video here.
Thank you very much for watching.
Bye-bye.